[narrator] Previously on The Big Bang Theory:
-Guess I'm your new neighbor. Penny.
-Oh. Leonard, Sheldon.
-Hi.
-[both] Hi.
-That's where I sit.
-Howard Wolowitz,
-Caltech Department of Applied Physics.
-Penny. Leonard. Raj.
[Howard] He speaks English.
He just can't speak to women.
Our babies will be smart and beautiful.
Finally caught a break.
♪ Soft kitty ♪
-You know my girlfriend, Bernadette.
-[Mrs. Wolowitz] Howard, I'm home!
♪ Warm kitty ♪
[screaming]
♪ Little ball of fur ♪
I'm Amy Farrah Fowler.
You're Sheldon Cooper.
-Bazinga.
-Whoa!
[horns honking]
-[Penny screams]
-[Sheldon screams]
Welcome to the premier episode
of Sheldon Cooper Presents: Fun with Flags.
I'm going up in space.
Technically, I'm an astronaut.
Oy vey!
You're talking to me.
-I am.
-[gasps]
Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski...
[all] We now pronounce you
husband and wife.
Amy. Howard. Angry Amy.
I don't want you to say it just
because social convention dictates--
-I love you too.
-Will you marry me?
Yes.
We did it!
Well, I enjoyed that
more than I thought I would.
I wonder which one's Halley.
[baby squalling in nasal voice]
-Will you marry me?
-That means positive?
Super-asymmetry, that's it.
Our paper was right. We did it.
-We did it?
-We did it.
♪ Six times 10 to the eighth atoms
Of radium in a lead jar ♪
♪ Six times 10 to the eighth atoms of radium ♪
♪ If the half-life of radium
Should happen to pass ♪
♪ Three times 10 to the eighth atoms
Of radium in a lead jar ♪
Really hope you're almost to zero.
That's the beauty of half-lives. It's impossible
to determine when you'll arrive at zero.
It's like "Wheels on the Bus"
if the bus had an unknowable number of parts.
-Yeah, we're gonna need more coffee.
-Yep, I'm with you.
-Leonard, coffee?
-Black and strong like Luke Cage.
Too tired to even be disturbed by that.
-Sheldon?
-Absolutely not.
The Nobel Committee will be making the calls
to inform the winners at any minute,
so the only drug I need is the endorphins
pumping through my brain
in anticipation of our victory.
Well, technically, anticipation wouldn't be
mediated by endorphins as much dopamine,
but you've been up all night,
so I'll give you that one.
Really? The second he stops talking?
Well, should we wake him up?
He did say if he fell asleep,
we were allowed to slap him awake.
Oh, boy.
-Wait a minute, why do you get to do it?
-I called it.
-You can't just call it. You have to earn it.
-Oh, and you've earned it?
No one has earned it more than me.
[Amy clears throat]
You have your whole life to smack him around.
This is my time.
Fine, don't miss.
It's not a volleyball. I can handle it.
[Penny] Oh, wait, hang on.
When you're old,
you are gonna want a record of this.
Oh, yeah, do it in slow-mo.
I wanna see his cheeks ripple.
Ready, go.
-[cell phone ringing]
-[gasps] It's happening!
-Unknown caller. It's gotta be them.
-Put it on speaker.
-Hello.
-Hi.
[man with rhotacism]
Hello, this is Sweden calling.
Is this Dr. Cooper and Dr. Fowler?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
Congratulations,
it is my pleasure to inform you
that you've won
the Nobel Prize in being suckers!
His Swedish accent was very convincing.
-[cell phone ringing]
-[gasps] This is it.
-What do you want, Howard?
-We were just calling to see if you'd heard yet.
We haven't.
But thank you for getting up so early to call.
That was very thoughtful.
Oh, please, we have two little kids.
We've been up for an hour.
-[Howard] Did anyone get to slap Sheldon?
-No.
All right, call us when you hear.
All right, now what?
Why don't we play a game to pass the time?
Here. I'm thinking of a number.
Hint: It's a cube of a cube of a prime.
-There's an infinite number of possibilities.
-You got somewhere to be?
-[cell phone ringing]
-Oh, that's me.
Hello?
Yes, this is Dr. Fowler.
I see.
Okay, thank you.
We won.
Congratulations!
Oh, my God.
-We did it.
-[Amy] I know.
-Can you believe it?
-That's a good point. What if I'm dreaming?
[Penny screams]
We won the Nobel Prize!
[all screaming]
♪ Our whole universe was in
A hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years ago
Expansion started-- Wait ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool
The autotrophs began to drool ♪
♪ Neanderthals developed tools
We built a wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, science, history
Unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ It all started with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
How does it feel to be married
to a Nobel Prize winner?
You tell me.
Oh. Amy-centric, what a fun way to look at it.
-I think so.
-You would. That makes sense.
-[cell phone buzzes]
-Ooh.
Aw. It's a congratulations text
from my Meemaw.
-[cell phone buzzes]
-Oh, there's one from my mom.
-And my sister.
-[cell phone buzzes]
-And my brother.
-And my brother's ex-wife.
-[cell phone buzzes]
-And my brother's other ex-wife.
Boy, they don't tell you when you win
a Nobel it chews up your phone battery.
-[cell phone buzzes]
-[Amy] Oh, that's me.
It's CVS. My prescription's ready.
[cell phone buzzes]
Oh, and also my dad.
He says congratulations and he loves me.
Nothing about me?
-[cell phone buzzes]
-Oh.
Oh, it's your dad. I'm good.
You know, when you think about it,
now that we're Nobel Prize winners,
our names will be linked together forever.
We're married.
Our names are already linked together forever.
Please, that's just a piece of paper.
This is a piece of paper and a medal.
It's weird, I don't really feel different,
but I guess our lives will never be the same.
I don't know. We're going to work like always.
I still put my pants on both legs at a time.
One day that's gonna end very badly.
-[reporter 1] Oh! Dr. Cooper!
-[reporter 2] Dr. Fowler!
[reporters clamoring]
Congratulations. How does it feel?
Okay, we're happy to answer your questions.
Just, um, one at a time, please.
-Is Dr. Cooper coming back?
-No. Next question.
[reporters] Dr. Fowler!
Was it your left hand or your right hand?
Right.
Spit actually flew out of his mouth.
[Siebert] Hey, fellas.
-Can you do me a favor?
-Do we have a choice?
No.
Sheldon and Amy are now officially superstars,
and the press will be reaching out
to their family and friends.
So that we're all on the same page, the word
we're gonna use to describe them is "quirky."
-And not "quirky." More like "quirky."
-So not Mr. and Mrs. Wackadoodle?
You bitter, envious little man.
Thank you so much.
And what do we call that?
[all] Quirky.
Dr. Cooper, can I get a minute of your time?
Hello?
Hey, can I help you?
Yeah, actually, um, I had an appointment
to interview Dr. Cooper about the Nobel.
Hang on a second.
Sheldon?
Sorry, he's not here.
Damn, I've got a deadline.
I don't know if it helps you at all,
but I'm his best friend in the whole world.
-Really?
-And an astronaut.
Come on, you can buy me a cup of coffee
and I'll tell you about both.
[Amy sobbing]
Everyone okay in there?
[Amy] Go away.
Amy?
Raj, please, not now.
Hey, what's wrong?
My picture's all over the Internet
and I look terrible.
No, let me see.
Well, that is an unfortunate angle.
But who cares?
You just won the Nobel.
You should be proud of this moment.
I know I shouldn't care about how I look
and I never thought I did.
It's stupid and shallow, but I just can't help it.
Am I really this frumpy?
No. No, you are a beautiful woman.
If you're not happy with those pictures,
then make some changes.
Get a haircut, new clothes,
new glasses, big glasses--
No glasses.
Then you won't be able to see those pictures.
Sounds expensive.
Excuse me, if I'm not mistaken, the Nobel
comes with a substantial cash prize.
What were you gonna spend it on?
I hadn't really thought about it.
Sheldon's got his eyes on some new Dockers.
Come on, do something for yourself.
Well, I suppose I could get a haircut.
And some makeup, and a new wardrobe,
and a little thank-you gift
for your shopping buddy
if we see something he likes. Come on.
-Where are we going?
-Beverly Hills, where the things he likes are.
Dinner ready?
Not unless you cooked.
Why is this article
about Sheldon all about you?
Let me see.
Oh, good, they used my NASA picture.
Why does it say that you're his best friend?
Leonard's his best friend.
No, Leonard has always been
kind of a monkey butler.
Whenever Sheldon got into a scrape,
I was his go-to guy.
When did he get into a scrape?
You're kidding, right?
Remember when he had a panic attack
because his hand got stuck in a jar of olives?
I was the one who told him
to let go of the olives.
Please, that doesn't make you his best friend.
[scoffs]
You know, that reporter asked me if I could
put him in touch with Amy's best friend.
-That's Penny.
-[singsong] Doesn't have to be.
Hmm.
What kind of tea is appropriate
for winning a Nobel Prize
and now everything is changing
and you feel unmoored from reality?
I don't know, Earl Grey?
You know, this is something
I've wanted my whole life,
but I never considered
how everything would be different.
I know it all feels overwhelming right now,
but I promise you things will settle down.
There's no Earl Grey, you filthy liar.
[knocking on door]
-Hey, is Penny here?
-No, why?
I wanted to show her my latest creation.
I give you...
Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler.
Wow, Amy, you look amazing.
Thank you.
Sheldon, what do you think?
I like you better the way you were.
But she looks beautiful.
Classic lines,
colors that complement her skin tone,
and hair that goes from "office"
to "on the town" in minutes.
I don't care. Put it back.
-I like the way I look.
-Well, I don't.
My fault. I was out of Earl Grey. [clears throat]
Sheldon, that was really rude.
I'm sorry. Amy's the one constant
I can count on and now she's changing.
It's just a haircut and some clothes.
No, it's the last straw. I can't take any more.
[elevator bell dings]
Can you believe it?
They finally fixed the elevator.
This is a nightmare.
What's with him?
He won a Nobel Prize
and his wife looks amazing.
Oh, yeah, got it.
[gasping]
-How did you get down here?
-Elevator, it's really fast.
I need to be alone right now.
Don't try to follow me.
-All right. Do you need a ride?
-That'd be great, thank you.
I should've seen this coming.
-Oh, stop, you're allowed to get a haircut.
-I know, but I should've done it gradually.
You know, like...
maybe 300 tiny haircuts over a 10-year period.
Okay, you need to focus on the positive.
You won a Nobel Prize. I slapped Sheldon.
A lot of dreams came true today.
You know, you're right.
This is a huge day for me,
and I'm allowed to enjoy it without worrying
how it's going to affect my husband.
Is it me or did it just get fierce in here?
All this change is just too much.
The reporters, the attention at work,
and now even Amy's changed.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down.
I'm playing a drinking game.
Every time you say "change," I take a slug.
-Are you gonna be able to drive me home?
-Mm, not unless you change the subject. Oh.
Now I said it. Wah.
You're the only person
who could win the biggest prize in science
-and still be upset about it.
-It's just...
all the times I thought about winning,
I never thought about how it would ch--
Affect my life.
I'm sorry,
I'm genuinely concerned about your liver.
Okay.
Fine, I'll stop playing.
You go on and on about
wanting things to stay the same,
but you've changed a lot since I met you.
Oh, you are a mean drunk.
I'm serious.
You have a ton of friends, you got married,
moved into a new apartment,
you wore a baseball hat that one time.
Heck, you've had sex almost
as many times as I have fingers.
-More.
-[Penny] Wha...
By this many.
You dog.
-It was the Avengers trailer.
-Oh. Mm-hm.
I've grown too.
I used to be the bartender back there.
[Sheldon] That's true.
And now there's a completely different woman
who botched my drink order.
How hard is 65 percent Coke,
35 percent Diet Coke?
Judging by the look on her face,
it's at least 1 percent saliva.
But I do take your point. You're also married,
you have a successful career,
you no longer dress like you're
trying to attract sailors by the wharf.
So I guess the only thing
that actually stays the same
is that things are always changing.
Interesting.
So you're saying the inevitability of change
might be a universal constant.
Well, there's a little more
to it than that but, yeah, sure.
Oh, hey, look, it's Bernadette.
I can't tell you how many times
Dr. Fowler was gonna give up,
and I would say to her,
"Amy, as your best friend,
I am not gonna let you quit."
Okay, I'm drinking again.
I'll join you.
Waitress, 95 percent Hawaiian Punch,
5 percent vodka.
Let me tell you about the time
Mr. Nobel Laureate wanted olives.
This is a good one.
You know what, 90/10.
You know, I like the way my hair looks.
I'm done tiptoeing around him.
We're all guilty of it.
But why?
-We were afraid to upset him.
-Which happens anyway.
-Well, that's over.
-I'm done enabling him.
Like this is his spot, and the thermostat
has to be set to his comfort level
even though he doesn't even live here
and I'm always chilly.
Is that why you wear a hoodie all the time?
Why would--? Yes!
To accommodate Sheldon.
And what about this thing?
Why is it here? I'll tell you why.
Because it was here when I moved in,
and for no earthly reason,
he forbade me to touch it.
Well, if you don't like it, get rid of it.
Put it in the closet.
You know what, I will.
I bet that's the reason.
Hang on.
What do you think? Wanna give it a try?
[elevator bell dings]
Well, the elevator did work
when I moved into the building,
so going up and down the stairs was a change,
which means this would actually
be a return to the status quo.
-But conversely--
-Get in.
[Sheldon] This is wild.